

Creative Technologist (they/them) davrc.me@gmail.com

Telephone → +44 7588 580080 Portfolio → https://devushkabeam.netlify.com LinkedIn → www.linkedin.com/in/rollinson-david

Future-focused, conscientious, and highly creative computational artist and designer with several years' experience in creative technology projects and collaboration. Enjoys interfacing multiple technologies together to create feature-rich interactive work. An extremely conscientious, rapid learner who enjoys going beyond the call of duty in developing inventive solutions to problems. References available upon request.

WORK HISTORY

• Freelance Creative Technologist for Creative Commissions | Southeast London - 06/2022 - Present.

Developing software and web-based audio-visual systems using C++, Java, GLSL, Blender (see portfolio link above). Web development in Vue.js and Next.js using headless CMS.

Administrative responsibilities such as authoring treatments, speculative budgeting, and client negotiation.

Creative Technologist in Residence | The Beams, Centre for New Culture - 03/2023 - 06/2023.

'Impure Functions'- audience-facing residency, communicating and demonstrating digital arts practice live to a public audience. Rapid prototyping of interactive artworks to exhibit using Processing, GLSL, Stable Diffusion, Arduino & PureData.

Led skill-share workshop, teaching GLSL & GPU architecture to compeers.

Compiled and authored showcase press release and schedule. Created and handled audio-visual marketing material for socials.

• Artist Technical Assistant | The Beams, Centre for New Culture - 03/2023 - 06/2023.

'Cyclops Retina: Light Barrier 2.4' - assisting Studio Kimchi & Chips with calibration of light projections onto large scale mirror array. Stable diffusion, Blender, Adobe AE, Premiere and OpenFrameworks graphics development.

Negotiating fire safety assessment timeline with technician crew & equipment inventorying.

• Digital Arts Exhibition Co-Organiser | Goldsmiths, University of London - 01/2022 - 05/2022.

Authored positioning statement & oversaw development of a cohesive aesthetic identity, prioritising tasks to external deadlines. Strengthened online presence by developing engaging & consistent content generating 1000+ impressions.

• Student and Department Representative | Goldsmiths, University of London - 09/2019 - 09/2021.

Collaborated with department to define key learning metrics, identifying scopes to enhance overall study. Spoke publicly, delivering informative presentations to prospective department applicants.

• Sales Associate in Luxury Fashion | Déjà Vu Boutique, Malvern – 02/2017 – 01/2018.

Managed dress agency appointments and stock, boosting sales by identifying and rectifying customer experience bottlenecks.

SKILLS AND TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

- **Programming languages:** C++, OpenGL (GLSL), C#, Python, Web (Vue, Next.js, Strapi CMS) & Git versioning.
- Advanced Arduino: OOP, proto-threaded latency reduction, power management in creative installation contexts.
- OpenFrameworks (C++): 3D programming, UX design, unifying soft + hardware frameworks: Kinect SDK, Ableton Live, Arduino, Sensors, GLSL.
- **Unity Scripting in C#:** undertaking short personal games projects OOP.
- **Shader Programming: in** GLSL, hash noise algorithms, raymarching. Extending GLSL interactivity using Processing/C++ & external sensor inputs.
- Blender and Autodesk Fusion modelling: procedural shading, modelling (geo nodes) & rendering in Cycles.
- Industry Standard Systems: Adobe CC Suite, Ableton Live, Rhino Grasshopper, Cloud Computing.
- Soft Skills: communication, adaptability, critical thinking, troubleshooting & problem solving.

EDUCATION

BSc Computational Arts | Joint Hons. in Creative Computation and Critical Theory.

First Class Hons. at Goldsmiths, University of London. Sample of classes taken: Critical Arts Studies, Machine Learning, Computer Graphics (GLSL), Digital Media Studies, Advanced Audio-Visual Programming, Physical Computing, Numerical Mathematics.

· UAL Foundation Diploma in Fine Art | XD Pathway for Immersive Experience Design.

Full-marks Distinction at Hereford College of Art. Received 'College Award 2019' for Creative Originality & Outstanding Development.

· A-Levels in Economics, Mathematics and Linguistics.

PROJECTS

- Conceived a mini-portfolio of 8 browser-based ML artworks demo-ing ML models & systems: ml5.js, p5.js, HTML and TensorFlow.
- Developed several short web games narrative conception, wireframing, progression mechanics, programming and deployment.
- Conceived and exhibited an installation artwork utilized Arduino electronics and custom DAW plugin for public exhibition.
- Public installation project conceptualised, designed and created multisensory installation artwork, inc. woodwork, 3D printing, custom electronics, StyleGAN2-ADA (PyTorch ver.) video, programmed 3D interactive graphics using structured-light data from Xbox Kinect. Exhibited at Bargehouse Gallery, Southbank May '22.

INTERESTS include the built environment, electronics, creative applications for ML, eastern European history and classical flute.